Guide to the Papers of Abby Weed Grey 1922-1978 MC 151
New York University Archives
- Series XVI: Multimedia Collection
  - 1) Ben Dehler 6/9/77 2) Lawrence Boland Sunrise Semester, Jun 9, 1977 (Box 12, Cassette 4)
  - Parviz & Slides, undated (Box 12, Cassette 5)
  - 1) Art Purchases from 1st - Thru Clara 2) Paris letters (4/27/76), Apr 27, 1976 (Box 12, Cassette 6)
  - Aug. 14, 1975 Interview #2 (Box 12, Cassette 7)
  - Aug. 26, 1975 (Box 12, Cassette 8)
  - Grey Gallery NYU Dec., 1974 (Box 12, Cassette 9)
  - 1) "Fakir" Interview- 1st meeting with Parviz 2) Film: Shirz Kavir-Lute, undated (Box 12, Cassette 10)
  - Aug. 5, 1975 Interview #1 (Box 12, Cassette 11)
  - 1) Houses I have lived in 2) 497 Otis home (Not transcribed) 2/3/76, Feb 3, 1976 (Box 12, Cassette 12)
  - Deer Lake - Sept. 18-Oct. 19, 1953, Fall 1953 (Box 12, Cassette 13)
  - Description of Deer Lake 12/7/75, Dec 7, 1975 (Box 12, Cassette 14)
  - Aug. 19, 1975 Interview #3 (Box 12, Cassette 15)
  - Margaret Cornelius 6/8/77, Jun 8, 1977 (Box 12, Cassette 16)
  - 1) "Common Ground" with the Mariers 2) Postman - "radio" 12/29/76, Dec 29, 1976 (Box 12, Cassette 17)
  - Oct. 6, 1975 - Abby Weed Grey Interview (Box 12, Cassette 18)
  - Early Years thru page 14, undated (Box 12, Cassette 19)
  - E.L. on Heline's 1st chapter 6/1/81, Jun 1, 1981 (Box 12, Cassette 20)
  - Conversation-Oct. 9, 1982 - St. Paul, MN Parviz Tanavoli & Abby Weed Grey, Sep 9, 1982 (Box 12, Cassette 21)
  - Green And Blue America. Wallace Stevens, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225398 2
    large reel
  - Pictures at an American Exhibition (First Answer Print), undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Jamshid Salt Village, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Abby Weed Grey Where?, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Orig: High Contract Titles/Credits Iran 1970 A. Wind B. Wind Also Poet/Philosopher (Box 13 A, Folder 6)
    3 small reels in one container.
    Preservation inspection report held at University Archives.
  - Narration-Jacques Poet/Philosopher, Iran 1970 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Poet/Philosopher, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Poet/Philosopher, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    large reel.
  - Poet/Philosopher - Can 3 - Music Trx. A" Effx, undated (Box 13 A, Folder 10)
    2 reels in 2 containers.
  - Poet/Philosopher - Can 4 - Narration Trx. "B" Effx., undated (Box 13 A, Folder 11)
    2 large reels in 2 containers.
  - Poet/Philosopher - Can 6 - Extra Transfer of Narration/Out Takes, undated (Box 13 B, Folder 12)
    12 small reels in two large film containers. Preservation inspection report held at University Archives.
  - Poet/Philosopher - Can 7 - Extra Transfer of Narration and Sound, undated (Box 13 C, Folder 13)
  - Poet/Philosopher - Can 9 - Pix Outs and Trims, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    5 small reels in large blue case. Preservation inspection report held at University Archives.
  - Poet/Philosopher - Can 9 - Pix Outs and Trims One over-sized reel-too large for a box entitled Spring in Iran" located under Box 4, in metal reel container, undated (Box 13 A, Folder 15)
    Five small reels contained within one large container.
  - "Spring in Iran", undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - "Spring in Iran", undated (Box 14A, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225400 6
  - Poet & Philosopher, ca. 1970 (Box 14A, Folder 2)
    Technical Requirements
    Access copy available.
- Series XVII: Abby Weed Grey Photographs
  Scope and Content
  The photos are housed in 5 flat boxes. Inclusive dates are 1962-1982, although the bulk consists of photos from 1965-68.
  - Subseries A: Exhibitions 1962-1972
    - Communication Thru Art, A.F.A Opening, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225401 4
    - Communication Thru Art, Lahore, Pakistan, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Turkish Art Today, Opening Installation, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - National College of Arts Gift, Pakistan, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - American Prints Exhibit, Iran-American Society Building Opening, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - University of Tehran Foundry, Students Exhibit, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Communication Thru Art, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Communication Thru Art, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - 1st Triennale of World Art, India, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Communication Thru Art, Indian Tour, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - M.A.P. Party, Jan 11, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Communication Thru Art, S. India, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - 10 Young American Artists, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225402 2
    - Communication Thru Art, India, Book Presentation, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - MCAD Exhibition, Installation, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Turkish Art, SUNY Binghamton, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Contemporary Turkish Painting, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - One World Thru Art, Installation, Minn State Fair, Jun 7, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - One World Thru Art -mounted, Jun 7, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - One World Thru Art -mounted, Jun 7, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Personal and Publicity
    - Benjamin Grey & Abby Weed Grey-Early, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225403 0
    - Abby Weed Grey-Publicity, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Abby Weed Grey & Thomas Waite-curator, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Deqhani-Tafti, Hassam (Angelican Bishop of Iran), undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Subseries C: Grey Gallery-St. Paul
    - Grey Gallery at 4997 Otis St., St. Paul, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D: Grey Gallery-NYU
    - Opening & Collateral, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Grey Art Gallery & 3rd Floor Main, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Iranian Art Today, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Lion Rug Exhibit, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Tanavoli Exhibit, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Works Donated, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Subseries E: Artist Photos
    - Communication Thru Art, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Aslier, Mustafa & Berk, Nurullah-Turkey, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Ayden, Necat-Turkey, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Berger, Aliye-Turkey, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225404 8
    - Eyuboglu, Bedri Rahmi, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Golzari, Behrooz-Iran, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Jamshid, Khagam; Siah, Armanjami; Parviz, Tanavoli, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Koral, Fureya-Turkey, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Kut, Mushin-Turkey, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Varlik, Utku-Turkey, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Subseries F: Tanavoli, Parviz
    - Miscellaneous-Publicity Photos, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Foundry at University of Tehran, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Tanavoli Bronze-Pahlavi University, Shraz, Iran, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Tanavoli with 2 children, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Tanavoli Art work, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Subseries G: Artwork
    - Grey Collection Art, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Guinis, Alkis (Greek Artist) *From Abby Weed Grey Papers Box 3, Fldr. 29, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Padamsee, Akbar (Indian Artist) *From Abby Weed Grey Papers Box 4, Fldr. 31, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Artwork (Seichrist, Ron) *From Abby Weed Grey Papers Box 5, Fldr. 29, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Subseries H: Miscellaneous
    - Contact Sheets, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Snapshots, Nov 4, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Snapshots, Nov 10, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous Snapshots, Nov 23, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous Snapshots, Dec 1, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225405 5
    - Student Sculpture Party, Feb 1, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Traveling with the Bishop of Iran (Evangelism in a Moslem world) *From Abby Weed Grey Papers Box 3, Fldr. 23, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Blind Students of Braille School, Isfahan, Iran, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Snapshots, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Series XVIII: Unprocessed
  - From Abby's Day Book, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225406 3
  - Press Releases, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Biography, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Catalogue-Todd Watts, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Biography, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 8)